For justice. For pride. For freedom.
Free State of Jones is a action, drama, history film directed by Gary Ross.
In 1863, Mississippi farmer Newt Knight serves as
a medic for the Confederate Army.
Opposed to slavery, Knight would rather help the wounded than fight the Union.
After his nephew dies in battle, Newt returns home to Jones County to
safeguard his family but is soon branded an outlaw deserter.
Forced to flee, he finds refuge with a group of
runaway slaves hiding out in the swamps.
Forging an alliance with the slaves and other farmers, Knight
leads a rebellion that would forever change history.
Newton Knight, played by Matthew McConaughey.
Rachel, played by Gugu Mbatha-Raw.
Moses Washington, played by Mahershala Ali.
Serena Knight, played by Keri Russell.
Daniel, played by Jacob Lofland.
Sumrall, played by Sean Bridgers.
Free State of Jones is a 2016 American historical war film inspired by the life of Southern Unionist Newton Knight, who led a
successful armed revolt against the Confederacy in Jones County, Mississippi, throughout the American Civil War.
Written, co-produced, and directed by Gary Ross based on a story by Ross and Leonard Hartman, the
film stars Matthew McConaughey, Gugu Mbatha-Raw, Mahershala Ali, and Keri Russell.
The story is based on the history of Jones County, Mississippi,
during the Civil War and the period immediately after it.
The overall story follows the history of Jones County;
some of the events portrayed are true.
The film is credited as being "based on the books The
Free State of Jones by Victoria E.
Bynum and The State of Jones by Sally Jenkins and John Stauffer."
It was
released in the United States by STXfilms on June 24, 2016.
It received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $25
million against its $50 million production budget.
The tone is emotional.